rosettastone.co.uk 2010-06-19

# Privacy Policy | Rosetta Stone

Rosetta Stone (UK) Limited (“Rosetta Stone”) takes the privacy of our customers seriously. We are committed to safeguarding your privacy while providing a personalised and valuable service.

## Overview

This Privacy Policy statement explains the data processing practices of Rosetta Stone. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any questions about these practices please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at [privacyofficer@rosettastone.com](mailto:privacyofficer@rosettastone.com). We encourage you to periodically review this statement as it may change at any time at our sole discretion.

Our site contains links to third party sites, which are not subject to this privacy policy. Rosetta Stone does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content on these sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit.

Information provided by you may be requested from one of our websites under the Rosetta Stone or Rosetta World brand names, or from one of our reputable co-marketing partner sites that represent our brands on their own websites under their company and/or brand name. In the event that you provide us with personal information for the purposes of free registration and you later make a purchase, whether directly from us or facilitated by one of our e-commerce partners, your privacy rights will be protected according to our stated policies and the stated privacy policies of these partners, which will be posted and available for your review at the time of purchase. 

## Information Collected 

Personal information is collected by Rosetta Stone. We collect personally identifiable information about you (your “Data”) through: 

  * The use of inquiry and registration forms.
  * The purchase process when you buy any of our products or services 
  * The provision of your details to us either online or offline 

The elements of your Data that we collect may include: 

  * Name 
  * Job title 
  * Company name 
  * Home, shipping and billing addresses, phone and fax number 
  * Mobile telephone number 
  * E-mail address 
  * IP address and browser information 
  * Payment details such as credit card information 
  * Market research data such as customer usage patterns

## Use and Disclosure of Personal Information 

We use your Data for purposes, which may include: 

  * Providing our customers with a personalized service. 
  * Processing orders, registrations and inquiries. 
  * Conducting market research surveys. 
  * Running competitions. 
  * Measuring interest in and improving our website, products, and services.
  * Providing you with information about products and services we offer. You may stop the delivery of marketing emails by following the instructions accompanying a particular communication or by contacting us at [privacyofficer@rosettastone.com](mailto:privacyofficer@rosettastone.com). 
  * Resolving disputes, collecting fees, and troubleshooting problems. 

We use the information you provide when placing an order to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except 1. To the extent necessary to complete that order or to provide services where the outside party is acting on our behalf and has no independent right to use the information we provide (e.g., third-party shipping, business analytics, or customer support ), or 2. To successors in title to our business, or 3. In accordance with legal and regulatory requirements, or 4. As necessary, in Rosetta Stone’s sole discretion, to protect the perceived rights, safety and property of Rosetta Stone, users of our websites, and the public.

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when Personal Information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

Customers of Rosetta Stone’s learning programs understand and accept that any Personal Information provided by customers may be sent outside the country of collection and/or to persons or entities that are not subject to the same legal or regulatory requirements regarding data protection.

We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified): 

  * To build up marketing profiles 
  * To aid strategic development 
  * To audit usage of the site

## Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices 

We use cookies to help personalize your use of our sites. A cookie is a small piece of information which is sent to your computer’s hard drive by the web server so that the website can remember who you are. This information may include information relating to your use of our sites, information about your computer such as the computer’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at our site via a link from a third party site, the URL of the linking page. If you are a registered user this may include your name and email address for verification purposes. 

We use information from cookies for purposes, which may include: 

  * Identifying returning users and registrants 
  * Enabling you to move more easily around our site 
  * Tracking your use of our site to better develop our sites in accordance with your requirements 
  * Building up a demographic profile. 
  * If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy, you may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your computer can be found on [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the ‘manage cookies’ section. Alternatively go to the help menu within your Internet browser. 

From time to time we may permit 3rd party companies to set cookies on Rosetta Stone sites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site. 

## Security Policy 

Rosetta Stone has appropriate measures in place to help ensure that our users’ Data is protected against unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. Although we make reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that thieves could find a way to thwart our security systems. 

## Transfer of Data 

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process personal Data necessarily involves the transmission of Data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing Rosetta Stone sites and communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal Data outside of the country in which you reside, including in the United States. 

## Access to Data and Contact Info 

You may request a copy or send a correction of the personal information we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer at [privacyofficer@rosettastone.com](mailto:privacyofficer@rosettastone.com) or writing to:

Privacy Officer  
Rosetta Stone (UK) Limited   
378 Clapham Road   
London SW9 9AF   
United Kingdom

We may charge the allowable fee under applicable law for provision of this information. 

## Children Under 13 

This site is not intended for use by persons under thirteen (13) years of age. We do not intentionally collect any information on children under 13 years of age. We will undertake to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has notified us that any such details have been obtained. 

## Changes to this Policy 

This policy is effective July 15, 2009. From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy statement to reflect any changes to our privacy practices in accordance with changes in legislation, best practice or website enhancements. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the email address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our website.
